#### Curriculum Vitae Ega Kurnia Yazid

New York City, USA

yazidega@gmail.com

Contact Information Email: e.yazid@columbia.edu Website: kurniayazid.github.io

Linkedin:

linkedin.com/in/kurniayazid/

Github: github.com/kurniayazid ORCID: 0000-0002-5854-4620

Professional Summary Ega (he/him) is an MA student in Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences (QMSS) at Columbia University in the City of New York fully-funded by Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP) scholarship. Before this, he was a Research Assistant at the Department of Economics, and Research Fellow at the Disaster Management Research Unit (DMRU) Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS). At CSIS, he actively took part in writing analysis on development economics, disaster economics, and policy analysis. Besides, he also served to help the Senior Advisor to the Minister of National Developing Planning, Republic of Indonesia for Social Affairs and Poverty Reduction in producing the evidence-based recommendations. Ega also has experience as an Economic Researcher at Tenggara Strategics—a business and investment research and advisory institute founded by CSIS, The Jakarta Post, and Prasetiya Mulya University. As an economic researcher, he involved in wide-ranging economic-business or investment research projects from the gig economy to renewable energy investment. His research area includes development economics, environmental economics, health economics, disaster management, and digital economy. He received his bachelor's degree in economics from Universitas Gadjah Mada, Indonesia in 2019 under supervision of Professor Gumilang Aryo Sahadewo.

Education & Professional Certification

Master of Arts, Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences Sep 2022 - Present Columbia University, New York City, USA

Data Science Professional Certificate

Mar 2020

IBM

Certification ID: EAZ88LMHANAE

Bachelor of Science, Economics Universitas Gadjah Mada, Yogyakarta, Indonesia Aug 2015 - Jun 2019

#### Experiences

Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS)

Jan 2020 – Jul 2022

Role: Research Fellow at DMRU & Research Assistant at Department of Economics

- Conducts research and provides economic as well as statistical analysis
- Writes academic and policy papers from the analyses
- Involves thoroughly in departmental and unit projects from brainstorming for the research proposal to reporting the research results and evaluation

Ministry of National Development Planning, Indonesia Jun 2020 – Aug 2022 Role: Socioeconomic Modelling Specialist / Consultant

 Assists the Senior Advisor to Minister for Social Affairs and Poverty Eradication to prepare the policy briefs and advises regarding the socioeconomic issues and policies. Tenggara Strategics Feb 2020 – Dec 2020

Role: Economic Researcher

- Conducted research on the Grab Indonesia's economic contribution. Directly shared the report to the Grab's Indonesia Board of Directors.
- Wrote daily media monitoring on the current national affairs for both national and international clients.

# Publications & Research Projects

"G20 Toolkit for Measuring Digital Skills and Digital Literacy", 2022, published in collaboration with Oxford Digital Pathways, SMERU Institute, and Ministry of ICT Indonesia.

"Mapping The Wellbeing and Regeneration of Fisher Community", 2021, with Prof. Arief Anshory Yusuf, Prof. Nur Iriawan, Vivi Yulaswati, and Herman Palani, published at Bulletin of Statistics Community Forum (FMS)

"Tracking the Ups and Downs in Indonesia's Economic Activity During COVID-19 Using Mobility Index: Evidence from Provinces in Java and Bali", 2021, with Yose Rizal Damuri, Prabaning Tyas, Haryo Aswicahyono, Lionel Priyadi, and Stella Kusumawardhani, published in ERIA Discussion Paper Series.

"Bouncing Back: An Empirical Evidence of Aggregate Economic Impact of Disasters in Indonesia", 2021, with Esa Azali Asyahid, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Exploration of the Relationship between COVID-19 Cases and Google Search Trends in Indonesia", 2021, with Haryo Aswicahyono, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Readiness of Greater Jakarta hospitals key in mitigating spread of COVID-19", 2020, with Mikhail Gorbachev Dom, published on The Jakarta Post.

"Game Theory Behind the Dilemma of Homecoming Eid amid the COVID-19 Pandemic", 2020, with Fadli Jihad Dahana Setiawan, published in CSIS Commentaries.

## Computer & Programming Skills

Data Analysis Package: STATA, Python, R, Eviews

Data Management: SQL, IBM Cloud

Data Visualization: Tableau, Adobe (Photoshop, Premiere), Canva

Office & Collaborative Working: Ms Office, Trello, Teams, Google Workspace, GitHub

### Awards & Scholarship

- 1. Scholarship Awardee Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP)
- 2. 2nd Winner HackData (Hackathon + Datathon), Indosat Ooredo (2019)
- 3. 1st Winner Indonesia Economic Outlook'19, University of Indonesia (2018)
- 4. 1st Winner Taxplore Paper Competition, University of Indonesia (2018)
- 5. Semifinalist Deloitte Tax Challenge, Deloitte Touche Solutions (2018)
- 6. 3rd Winner & Best Delegate Ekonomi Bebas Korupsi VIII, Gadjah Mada University (2017)
- 7. 1st Winner Shariah Business Solution Business Case Competition, Gadjah Mada University (2017)
- 8. 2nd Winner Student Scientific Paper Contest, Institut Teknologi Bandung (2017)
- 9. 3rd Winner Development Economics Essay Competition, Universitas Parahyangan & Bank Indonesia